Chris Coenen Collection on General Tom Thumb MS254
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Printed ephemera, 1835 -- 1996; MS254.000866
  - Ad for Mrs. General Tom Thumb at Lyric Theatre, 1912; MS254.000990 (Box 9)
  - Ad for Mrs. Gen. Tom Thumb,71; Oneonta Theatre, 1912; MS254.000991 (Box 9)
    Ad for show in Oneonta
  - Ad for Grand Matinee with carriage on back, 1895; MS254.000992 (Box 9)
    Ad for show with carriage on back from photo
  - Ad for Mrs. Tom Thumb show; carriage on back, 1895; MS254.000993 (Box 9)
  - Ad for Mrs. General Tom Thumb Show with Jennie Quigley; carriage on back, 1896; MS254.000994 (Box 9)
    Ad for show with carriage
  - Ad for show with carriage on back, 1895; MS254.000995 (Box 9)
    Ad for show with carriage from photo
  - Ad for show with carriage on back; show time change, 1895; MS254.000996 (Box 9)
  - PT Barnum parody; "Every Man Rides His Own Hobby"; Jumbo, 1882; MS254.000997 (Box 9)
    PT Barnum parody; "Every Man Rides His Own Hobby"; Jumbo
  - Early woodcut of Charles Stratton, 1845; MS254.000998 (Box 9)
    Early woodcut of Charles Stratton
  - Early ad for Barnum's Museum with wedding group, 1863; MS254.000999 (Box 9)
    Early ad for Barnum's Museum with wedding group
  - Chromolithograph cards; Tom Thumb as Napoleon, 1880; MS254.001000 (Box 9)
    Chromolithograph cards; Tom Thumb as Napoleon
  - Miss Sarah Belton ad card for Liliputian Comic Opera Co., 1870; MS254.001001 (Box 9)
    Miss Sarah Belton ad card for Liliputian Comic Opera Co.
  - Ad card with Admiral Dot's carriage; drug ad on back, 1870; MS254.001002 (Box 9)
    Ad card with Admiral Dot's carriage; drug ad on back
  - Millie-Christine ad card, 1883; MS254.001003 (Box 9)
    Millie-Christine ad card
  - Ad for Alden's photography inside Barnum's Museum, 1864 -- 1868; MS254.001004 (Box 9)
    Ad for Alden's photography inside Barnum's Museum
  - Ad card for Demorest Emporium of Fashion; made wedding dresses, 1880; MS254.001005 (Box 9)
    Ad card for Demorest Emporium of Fashion; made wedding dresses
  - Early lithograph of Tom Thumb and his performances; digital copy only, 1844; MS254.001006 (Box 4)
    Early lithograph of Tom Thumb and his performances; digital copy only
  - Lithograph of Tom Thumb in France with carriage, 1845; MS254.001007 (Box 4)
    Lithograph of Tom Thumb in France with carriage
  - Print of General Tom Thumb as the Alarmed African, 1844; MS254.001008 (Box 4)
    Print of General Tom Thumb as the Alarmed African
  - Ad card for Mrs. General Tom Thumb at Trenton Theater, Lycnchburg, Va., 1912; MS254.001009 (Box 9)
    Ad card for Mrs. General Tom Thumb at Trenton Theater, Lycnchburg, Va.
  - Ad card for Capt. Geo. Auger, Welsh Giant; Barnum & Bailey, 1910; MS254.001010 (Box 9)
    Ad card for Capt. Geo. Auger, Welsh Giant; Barnum & Bailey
  - Large ad card for Mrs. Tom Thumb, Count and Baron Magri at The New Gilmore, 1910; MS254.001011 (Box 4)
    Large ad card for Mrs. Tom Thumb, Count and Baron Magri at The New Gilmore
  - Printed photo of Lavinia, 1910; MS254.001012 (Box 4)
    Printed photo of Lavinia
  - Mrs. General Tom Thumb and Count Magri; Family Theater, Worcester, Ma., 1910; MS254.001013 (Box 4)
    Mrs. General Tom Thumb and Count Magri; Family Theater, Worcester, Ma.
  - Reprint of a show progam from Ingomar Theatre, Humboldt, Ca., 1895 -- 1958; MS254.001014 (Box 4)
    Reprint of a show progam from Ingomar Theatre, Humboldt, Ca.
  - Ad for Taunton Theater with program announcing appearance of Mrs.Tom Thumb and tha Magris; Taunton, Ma., 1901; MS254.001015 (Box 4)
    Ad for Taunton Theater with program announcing appearance of Mrs.Tom Thumb and tha Magris; Taunton, Ma.
  - Flyer for show; carriage, 1890; MS254.001016 (Box 4)
    Generic show flyer with no location for "Two Strings To Her Bow"
  - Flyer for show; carriage; middle with carriage, 1890; MS254.001017 (Box 4)
    Middle of flyer showing carriage
  - Flyer for show; back page with program, 1890; MS254.001018 (Box 4)
    Back page with program
  - Ad for sale of cdv's of the "Little Marriage", 1863; MS254.001019 (Box 4)
    Ad for the sale of photos by Brady of the wedding group
  - Photo-Souvenir for Mrs.Gen. Tom Thumb, Cont and Baron Magri, 1895; MS254.001020 (Box 4)
    Sovenir sheet
  - Brochure: Biographical sketches of Mrs. Tom Thumb, Primo, ernesto and George Liable and Annie Nelson at Earles Court, London, 1898; MS254.001021 (Box 4)
    Eight page brochure with photos and biographical sketches of the American Lilliputian Co.
  - Phototype Souvenir; Academy of Music, Rochester, NY, 1894; MS254.001022 (Box 9)
  - Captain George Liable and Annie Nelson, 1890; MS254.001023 (Box 9)
    Travelled and performed with Lavinia's troupe
  - Programme; Deakin's Liliputian Comic Opera Company, 1875; MS254.001024 (Box 9)
    Cast includes Nutt and brother, Goshen, ennie Quigley, Maor Houghton, Sarah Belton
  - Small boadside for Tom Thumb Show; Barnum Museum, NY, 1860; MS254.001025 (Box 4)
    Newly returned from Europe with Barnum
  - Programme; Opera House; Mrs. Tom Thumb and Company; Trazom-"Hypno-Elecro Magia, 1895; MS254.001026 (Box 4)
    Program with the usual company including Jennie Quigley doing the "Hypno-Electro Magia" magic elevation trick
  - Mrs. General Tom Thumb and Count Magri in Nova Scotia, October 3, 1908, MS254.001027 (Box 4)
    Nova Scotia
  - Small broadside for Mrs. Gen. Tom Thumb Co.; Trazom, 1895; MS254.001028 (Box 4)
    Includes Chevalier Trazom doing "Hypno-Electro Magia"
  - Magazine page with repro ad for"Tom Tit" at American Museum with Tom Thumb, 1854 -- 1895; MS254.001029 (Box 4)
    Ad for Tom Tit; a play based on Uncle Tom's Cabin but with broad and somewhat racist humor with Tom Thumb playing Tom-Tit
  - Complimentary pass to Gen. Tom Thumb & Com. Nutt's Levee at St. James Hall, 1865; MS254.001030 (Box 9)
    Pass to show
  - Complimentary pass to General Tom Thumb's Entrtainment, 1865; MS254.001031 (Box 9)
    Pass for a show but not sure of date
  - Torn tickets to Mrs. Gen. Tom Thumb Co., 1890; MS254.001032 (Box 9)
    One of Lavinia's companies after Charles death
  - Print from Barnum's book Struggles & Triumphs (BST); St. Paul's, 1865; MS254.001033 (Box 4)
    Barnum kept updating his book with new prints; Victory over Vestrymen
  - Print BST; The Author Training Tom Thumb, 1865; MS254.001034 (Box 4)
    Before he appeared on stage, Barnum taught him various routines; Napoleon
  - Print BST; Tom Thumb and the Poodle, 1865; MS254.001035 (Box 4)
    On his first visit to Victoria, Tom sparred with her poodle
  - Print BST; The Great Duke and the Little General, 1865; MS254.001036 (Box 4)
    Tom meets the Duke of Wellngton
  - Print BST; Royal Honors to the General, 1865; MS254.001037 (Box 4)
    Tom is allowed to drive his carriage in the Longchamps parade, 1845
  - Print BST; Marriage in Miniature, 1865; MS254.001038 (Box 4)
    Barnum standing to the left
  - Print BST; Battle of the Giants, 1865; MS254.001039 (Box 4)
    Story from the book
  - Print BST; After the Fire, 1868; MS254.001040 (Box 4)
    Barnum's second museum burned in 1868
  - Print BST; The "Customs" of the Country, 1865; MS254.001041 (Box 4)
    Story from the book about getting posters through customs
  - Print BST; Welcome to Jenny Lind, 1865; MS254.001042 (Box 4)
    Barnum had hyped enny Lind's arrival
  - Article, with photo, of Countess Magri, Middleborough Gazette, 1920; MS254.001043 (Box 4)
    Article about Lavinia in her hometown newspaper
  - Article from Punch, British satire, about Barnum, 1857; MS254.001044 (Box 4)
    Punch liked to poke fun at Barnum and Tom Thumb
  - Article from Punch (?) about dwarfs; Tom Thumb and his Lifeguard, 1857; MS254.001045 (Box 4)
    Picture of Tom and the Queen's Guardsman
  - Middleboro Gazette article with photo of Lavinia painting, 1960; MS254.001046 (Box 4)
    Unknown date article with picture of Lavinia's portrait
  - Article about Commodore Nutt and Minnie Warren, 1950; MS254.001047 (Box 4)
  - Rest of article about Nutt and Minnie, 1950; MS254.001048 (Box 4)
    Article about Nutt and Minnie
  - Article with picture of Primo's Pastime, 1970; MS254.001049 (Box 4)
    MG article about Lavinia and Primo
  - Article about Barnum; Jumbo photo at Tufts, 1950; MS254.001050 (Box 4)
    Article about barnum
  - Rest of article about Barnum with a photo of Jumbo at Tufts, 1950; MS254.001051 (Box 4)
    Jumbo
  - Article scrap with picture of Lavinia and her brothers, 1910; MS254.001052 (Box 4)
    Article about Lavinia
  - Article srap with a picture of Lavinia's mother, 1910; MS254.001053 (Box 4)
  - MG article (Feb. 10, 1994) celebrating the anniversary of the wedding by the Middleborogh Historical Society, MS254.001054 (Box 4)
    Article about the wedding
  - Woodcut; Wedding Reception at the Metropolitan Hotel; German version of Frank Leslie's, 1863; MS254.001055 (Box 4)
    Copy of the original print from Leslie's
  - Woodcut: full page print of the wedding at Grace Church; Lesie's, German, 1863; MS254.001056 (Box 4)
    Full, double page spread
  - Woodcut; after the reception in their rooms; Lesie's, German, 1863; MS254.001057 (Box 4)
    Copy of the original from Leslie's
  - Tom Thumb; Jan Hannema, Dutch "Tom Thumb"; England, 1879; MS254.001058 (Box 4)
    Article and print of the Tom Thumb Wedding Party and Jan Hannema; The Penny Illustrated Paper
  - A Little Chapter on Dwarfs; article accompanying 861, 1879; MS254.001059 (Box 4)
  - Article and prints of Tom Thumb at Princess Theatre; Illustrated London News, 1844; MS254.001060 (Box 4)
    One of Tom's first performances in England; before he met the Queen
  - Article and prints of Tom Thumb at Princess Theatre; Illustrated London News II, 1844; MS254.001061 (Box 4)
    One of Tom's first performances in England; before he met the Queen; Barnum watches from the wing
  - Article on death of Primo Magri; MG, 1920; MS254.001062 (Box 9)
    Obituary for Count Magri
  - Newsphoto of Lavinia at seventy five; Springfirld SundayRepublican; 12/3/16, 1916; MS254.001063 (Box 4)
    Picture of Lavinia at her desk as Primo warches
  - Article From Scientific American 4/14/60, about a visit to Tom Thumb's show, 1860; MS254.001064 (Box 4)
    A visit to Tom Thumb's show
  - Our Trip Around the World; Sunday Magazine of the Minneapolis Journal, 10/21/06, 1906; MS254.001065 (Box 4)
    Lavinia reminisces about the round the world tour
  - Gleanings From My Autobiography; SMNJ; 12/16/06, 1906; MS254.001066 (Box 4)
    Article of snippets from Lavinia's autobiography
  - Unflattering article about Tom Thumb; Cincinnati Gazette; 12/13/79, 1879; MS254.001067 (Box 4)
    Article pointing out how much Tom Thumb has changed
  - Article about a visit to the Stratton's in Middleboro, 1875; MS254.001068 (Box 4)
    1870's article about a visit to their new home
  - Recollections of a Midget; Women's Home Companion; 10/00, 1900; MS254.001069 (Box 4)
    Stories about the Midgets
  - Newsphoto of Primo talking about setting up a Tom Thumb Museum; New York Times; 3/18/20, 1920; MS254.001070 (Box 4)
    Primo holds an old chair as he talks to a reporter in Middleboro; the items were eventually sold in an auction
  - Article in Scientific American, 7/67, about the genetics if dwarfs, ncluding Tom Thumb, 1967; MS254.001071 (Box 4)
    Geneticist describing the defect that produced Charles Stratton, with photo
  - Newspaper; Frank Leslie's Illustrated;2/21/63; Tom Thumb Wedding ething and ad, 1863; MS254.001072 (Box 4)
    Cover of paper with full page picture of Grace Church wedding and an ad Anthony photos of the wedding party
  - Engraving of the Church and Wedding, 1863; MS254.001073 (Box 4)
    Full page engraving of the wedding at Grace Church
  - Ad for photos of the wedding from Anthony & Co., 1863; MS254.001074 (Box 4)
    Photos of the Lilliputian Wedding
  - Newspaper ad for the American Museum; Newark Daily Advertiser; 2/23/47, 1847; MS254.001075 (Box 4)
    Ad fot Tom Thumb, newly returned from Europe
  - Newspaper; Nile's National Register 1/14/43; Six line news article about Tom Thumb, 1843; MS254.001076 (Box 4)
    Early piece about Tom Thumb; he would have ust turned five
  - News article about the death of Jumbo with photo of Jumbo at Tufts, 1910; MS254.001077 (Box 4)
    Early news article, date unknown, about the death of Jumbo with a photo of Martin Feeney visiting umbo at Tufts
  - Rest of article about Jumbo, 1910; MS254.001078 (Box 4)
  - Harper's Weekly 2/22/62; Ad for Commodore Nutt at the American Museum, 1862; MS254.001079 (Box 4)
    Ad for Nutt at the American Museum; he would have been recently hired by Barnum
  - Harper's Weekly 2/22/62; short article, probably penned by Barnum about Commodore Nutt at the American Museum, 1862; MS254.001080 (Box 4)
    Short article promoting Commodore Nutt
  - Gentry Bros. ad, 1913; MS254.001081 (Box 4)
    Lavinia, Primoa and Ernesto travelled with Gentry Bros. in 1907, mostly on the West Coast
  - Pamphlet with history of Magris and songs, 1898; MS254.001082 (Box 4)
    Date unknown; probably English
  - Engraving of Egyptiian Hall, London with Tom Thumb's carriage out front, 1846; MS254.001083 (Box 4)
    From "Illustrated London"; Egyptian Hall with Tom Thumb's carriage out front; he would ride the carriage to work, partly as a Barnum advertising scheme
  - British newspaper about King Edward with illustration of Tom Thumb and Royal Family; The Illustrated Bee, 6/22/02, 1902; MS254.001084 (Box 5)
    Litho of Tom Thumb's visit to meet young ,future King Edward, circa 1844
  - Newsphoto from an article about Famed Thespians; The Evening Bulletin, Philadelphia, 4/24/34, 1934; MS254.001085 (Box 5)
    Photo from a series; mislabled; really- Nutt, Lavinia, WB Harrison, Tom Thumb
  - Nespaper ad for Barnum's Circus, 7/1/81;Daily Journal, Evansville, Indiana; includes mention of Tom and Lavinia, 1881; MS254.001086 (Box 5)
    Large and graphic ad for Barnum Circus; this is the year Tom Thumb and wife travelled with the circus
  - Series of articles from The Strand Magazine about sideshow performers, 1905; MS254.001087 (Box 5)
    Circa 1905 series that includes Madame Mozarts (Trazour) hYpno-magia act which Lavinia also did
  - Article about Lavinia; Twentieth Century Review, 4/05; wedding cake donation, 1905; MS254.001088 (Box 5)
    Lavinia is worried she has been forgotten by the public
  - Mrs. Tom Thumb at Home; extensive article about Lavinia shortly after Charles Stratton's death; Harper's Young People, 3/4/84, 1884; MS254.001089 (Box 5)
    Long article about Lavinia's life before she re-married
  - Engraving of Barnum and article; Boston Museum, 10/26/50, 1850; MS254.001090 (Box 5)
    Paper produced by the Boston Museum with early article and engraving of Barnum
  - Engraving from Leslie's Illustrated of a presentation in Rochester, NY to Tom and Laviinia, 1864, MS254.001091 (Box 5)
    Also used as the illustration on a music sheet
  - Ad for Lavinia Warren at Barnum's Museum before she married Tom Thumb; New York Times, 1/19/63, 1863; MS254.001092 (Box 5)
    She had just begun working at the American Musem
  - Extensive article about the Tom Thumb Wedding, The Loving Lilliputians; New York Times, 2/11/63, 1863; MS254.001093 (Box 5)
    Long article about the wedding
  - Ad for Minnie Warren at the American Museum; New York Times, 2/15/63, 1863; MS254.001094 (Box 5)
    Minnie just started working for Barnum
  - Ad for Barnum's American Museum featuring Minnie Warren with engraving; New York Times, 2/23/63, 1863; MS254.001095 (Box 5)
    Minnie just started working for Barnum with engraving
  - Newspaper article about the wedding; The World,NY, 2/11/63, 1863; MS254.001096 (Box 5)
    Front page article describing the wedding
  - Front page of Harper's Weekly with portrait of Charles and Lavinia, 2/21/63, 1863; MS254.001097 (Box 5)
    Full page engraving and article
  - Harper's Weekly, back page ad for Minnie Warren at Barnum's American Museum, 2/21/63, 1863; MS254.001098 (Box 5)
    Shortly after the marriage, Barnum hired Minnie Warren; Nutt was already working at the Museum
  - Punch; Tom Thumb at the Palace with caricature, London, 1865; MS254.001099 (Box 5)
    Satire about the Queen patronizing Tom Thumb
  - Punch; Mr. Punch's Fancy Ball; satire with Tom Thumb, 1865; MS254.001100 (Box 5)
    Full page engraving satirizing celebrities
  - Punch; The Giant and the Dwarf; Thiers meets Tom Thumb, 1865; MS254.001101 (Box 5)
    French politician meets Tom as Napoleon; full page engraving
  - Magazine devoted to Victoria with print and short article about Tom Thumb's visit in 1844, 1901; MS254.001102 (Box 5)
    Reprint of and earlier engraving
  - Newspaper article on the death of Minnie Warren; 7/27/78; Cleveland Leader, 1878; MS254.001103 (Box 5)
    Article on Minnie's death
  - Newspaper article about the death of Lavinia Warren, 1919; MS254.001104 (Box 5)
    Article about Lavinia's death
  - Newspaper article about Primo Magri's death, 1920; MS254.001105 (Box 5)
    Article about Primo's death and the Tom Thumb auction
  - Article about Lavinia's birthday; 11/30/16; Leslie's; with photo, 1916; MS254.001106 (Box 5)
    Article about Lavinia's birthday with a photo of her with a camera and another of Tom and Lavinia's departure for Europe
  - Engraving of Commodore Nutt and Minnie Warren performing in England; Illustrated Times, 12/24/64, 1864; MS254.001107 (Box 5)
    Nutt and Minnie performed on their own in England
  - Ad for Nutt and Minnie appearing at St. James Hall; Illustrated Times, 12/24/64, 1864; MS254.001108 (Box 5)
    Nutt and Minnie appearing at St. James Hall for the holidays
  - Newspaper article; The Finding of Tom Thumb; Wellsville Daily Reporter, NY; 9/24/83, 1883; MS254.001109 (Box 5)
    Written shortly after Tom Thumb's death, a man from Bridgeport talks about helping to arrange a meeting with Charles Stratton and PT Barnum in Bridgeport
  - Article, The Ladies Home Journal, 5/99; long, illustrated article on the life of Lavinia Warren, 1899; MS254.001110 (Box 5)
    Long article with illustrations of the life of Countess Magri
  - Newspaper ad; NY Daily Tribune (Horace Greeley); early ad for Tom Thumb; 1/5/43, 1843; MS254.001111 (Box 5)
    Tom has just turned five; early ad for him performing at the American Museum
  - Newspaper ad for Barnum's travelling show; New Haven Daily Palladium, 6?51, 1851; MS254.001112 (Box 5)
    Ad with woodcut for Barnum's Caravan and managerie; including Tom Thumb; Thos. Tufts, agent
  - Newspaper article on Tom Thumb's Courtship; Vermont Chronicle; 8/28/69, 1869; MS254.001113 (Box 5)
    Article about Tom meeting and courting Lavinia
  - Article, ILN, 1/3/46; The English Tom Thumb with engraving, 1846; MS254.001114 (Box 5)
    Picture of the English Tom Thumb, now the Charles has left
  - Newspaper ad for Barnum's Travelling World's Fair; Harper's, 3/29/73, 1873; MS254.001115 (Box 5)
    Large illustration showing many of the attractions for an early version of his circus
  - Newspaper ad for The Siamese Twins; Troy Daily Whig, 6/17/35, 1835; MS254.001116 (Box 5)
    Chang and Eng worked briefly for Barnum after the war
  - Newspaper article about Lucia Zarate; The Congegationalist. 9/27/76, 1876; MS254.001117 (Box 5)
    Lucia was smaller then Tom (different dwarfism) and often compared to Tom Thumb
  - Article from the Pictorial Times, 1/3/46. about dwarfs; London, 1846; MS254.001118 (Box 5)
    Article talking about Tom Thumb and other dwarfs from history
  - Newspaper ad for Barnum's enterprises, including Tom Thumb; Vermont Watchman & State ournal, 8/17/55, 1855; MS254.001119 (Box 5)
    Ad for Barnum
  - Article from Punch; Tom Thumb and the Income Tax, 1845; MS254.001120 (Box 5)
    Barnum trying to avoid English taxes
  - Punch satire; The Irish Tom Thumb, 1845; MS254.001121 (Box 5)
    Satire using Tom Thumb
  - Punch satire; Tom Thumb at the Palace, 1845; MS254.001122 (Box 5)
    Satirizing the Queens patronage of Tom Thumb
  - Punch satire; Punch's Fine Art Exhibition, 1845; MS254.001123 (Box 5)
    Satirizing the Queens patronage of Tom Thumb; the statues may be a play on Tom Thumb's act
  - Newspaper ad; Tom Thumb and carriage; Daily Herald,Newburyport, 10/11/48, 1848; MS254.001124 (Box 5)
    Ad with engraving of the coach
  - Newspaper article; Tom Thumb at Ralston Hall; The Macon Telegraph and Messenger; Macon, Ga.; 4/4/76, 1876; MS254.001125 (Box 5)
    Tom Thumb show in Georgia
  - Article on Tom Thumb; Harper's Young People; 7/31/83, 1883; MS254.001126 (Box 5)
    Article on Tom Thumb's life puplished shortly after his death
  - Ad for Barnum's Greatest Show mentioning Tom Thumb; Nightly, Battle Creek, Michigan, 7/25/81, 1881; MS254.001127 (Box 5)
    Illustrated ad for the circus with Tom Thumb and Lavinia mentioned
  - Article with illustration of Lavinia's second marriage; Leslie's Illustrated,4/18/85, MS254.001128 (Box 5)
    Lavinia's second marriage at Trinity Church
  - Article about Tom Thumb leaving France; Nile's Nationa Register, 4/19/45, 1845; MS254.001129 (Box 5)
    Short article about Tom Thumb departing France
  - Article accompnying 938, 1885; MS254.001130 (Box 5)
  - Article with photo of Primo and newspaper reporter; New York Times Pictorial; 3/18/20, 1920; MS254.001131 (Box 5)
    After Lavinia's death, Primo is interviewed
  - Article; Demorest's Family Magazine,; article on midgets, including Tom Thumb, 1895; MS254.001132 (Box 5)
    Long article on midgets, mostly German dwarfs performing
  - Article on Tom Thumb as Mason; The Royal Arch Mason, 12/50, 1950; MS254.001133 (Box 5)
    Charles Stratton was a proud mason; Lavinia reportedly wore his insignia afterhis death
  - Article; St. Nicholas for Young Folks; illustrated article on General Tom Thumb, 1899; MS254.001134 (Box 5)
    Illustrated with copies of daguerreotypes
  - Article, The Century Magazine; life of Barnum, 1900; MS254.001135 (Box 5)
    By Benton, who wrote a biography of Barnum; some of his houses in Bridgeport are illustrated
  - Article; Recollections of a Midget; Mrs. Tom Thumb; 10/00; Women's Home Companion, 1900; MS254.001136 (Box 5)
    Article with photos of Lavinia's life
  - Article; Some Recollections by Mrs. Tom Thumb;New York Tribune, Sunday Magazine; 10/7/06, 1906; MS254.001137 (Box 5)
  - Ad for Barnum's Museum and Managerie; The Ohio Star7/14/52, 1852; MS254.001138 (Box 5)
    Barnum's travelling show with Tom Thumb
  - Article; The Philosophy of a Midget of 75 Years; The Post-dispatch, St. Louis; 11/16/16, 1916; MS254.001139 (Box 5)
    Article during Lavinia's 75th year
  - Article and engraving of the burning of Barnum's Museum; Harper's Weekly, 11/29/65, 1865; MS254.001140 (Box 5)
    Large engraving and article of the burning of Barnum's first museum
  - Article and photos; Boston Sunday Post, 11/19/16, MS254.001141 (Box 5)
    New England's Tiniest Woman Celebrates Her 75th Birthday
  - Engraving of the aftermath of the Barnum Museum fire, 1865; MS254.001142 (Box 5)
    Harper's engraving; 11/29/65
  - Engraving; The president passing through Broadway; Barnum Museum in the background; Gleason's Pictorial, 6/7/51, 1851; MS254.001143 (Box 5)
    Milard Fillmore's carriage on Broadway
  - Engraving; Barnum's Mammoth Tent; Gleason's Pictorial, 6/7/51, 1851; MS254.001144 (Box 5)
    Large tent fom Barnum
  - Engraving, satire; Lincoln,Barnum, Stratton and Nutt; The Coming Men; Leslie's, 2/28/63, 1863; MS254.001145 (Box 5)
    Satire on Lincoln and his generals
  - Engravings of the reception at the Metropolitan Hotel; Leslie's, 2/28/63, 1863; MS254.001146 (Box 5)
    Front page with multiple engravings
  - Ad with illustration; The Louisville Morning Courier, 4/4/48, 1848; MS254.001147 (Box 6)
    Ad for Tom's show
  - Ad for Barnum's Managerie and Circus; The Eastern Argus, Portland, Me.; 5/31/55, 1855; MS254.001148 (Box 6)